thethriftycouple.com 2019-06-11

# Privacy Policy

##### Updated May 2018 for GDPR Compliance

Know that our goal has been and continues to provide a safe haven for you as you search our site looking for encouragement along your own financial journey.  As you will see below, we only collect your email (when you offer it) to send emails you request.  You can see any other caveats below (e.g., IP address for reviewing trends in traffic) below.  We do not collect any additional personal information to allow you to maintain anonymity.

Note that at this time we are disabling all signup forms that offer a free product in exchange for signing up for a newsletter for any requests coming from the European Union.  This uses geo-location tools and may not be perfect but it is our best attempt at this time to be compliant with GDPR regulations.  Please note that we intend to re-enable those as soon as we can find a sufficiently compliant way to implement those forms with our tools.  The pop-up form at the top of the page that occasionally loads will remain as it explicitly asks for your email address to sign up for our newsletter, which our understanding is that is compliant with GDPR laws.

We do ask that you [contact us](https://thethriftycouple.com/contact-us/) with any concerns you might have.  We run this site very frugally (possibly too much so at times) and without as much return on our investment as many sites like ours.  Our goal is to provide a ministry and help to those that request it and we attempt to be consistent by to our mission by not charging unnecessary or extravagant amounts to access our site; honestly the bulk majority of the time it is free.  As such, we hope that you respect us as much as we respect you and ask that you would privately work with us to improve our site first before any other recourse is taken.  We believe you will find us eager to update anything we have unintentionally missed to improve your user experience moving forward. 

##### Your Privacy

Please always know that your privacy is a top priority for Alex & Cassie Michael and TheThriftyCouple.com!  Any information that you might share with us by any method will not be shared, sold, or used in any malicious way.  Any information you provide to us will not be publicly posted without your written permission.  Our goal is to protect your information while making this site a safe haven for you to learn how to save and become more a more thrifty family.  We encourage you to view our privacy policy below and let us know if you have any questions by visiting our [Contact Us](https://thethriftycouple.com/contact-us/ "Contact Us") page.

##### E-mails Collected in Comments

We understand your right to your own privacy!  We will never sell or provide your email that you give us to a third-party.  Any emails will be solely used to announce giveaway winners (without exposing the full email address) or contacting you in regards to a giveaway or amazing idea that you might have shared.  We hate spam and figure you probably do too!

##### Google Adsense and the DoubleClick Cookies

A “cookie” is a small snippet of text that is stored on your web browser.  Google uses such cookies to assist them to serve up ads that are most relevant and interesting to you.  If any time you wish to opt out of these cookies used on your browser, you may go to the [Google Privacy Center](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html "Google Privacy Center") and simply click on Opt Out.  DoubleClick cookies may also be used in conjunction with any advertising by Google.  Please refer to the Google Privacy Center as referenced above for additional information.

##### Collection of Personal Information

When accessing our site, small bits of information such as the IP address used to access the site will be logged along with the dates and times of access may be collected.  This information is purely used to analyze trends, administer the site, track users movement and gather broad demographic information for internal use.

This privacy policy sets out how The Thrifty Couple LLC. uses and protects any information that you give while using TheTheThriftyCouple.com

Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

The Thrifty Couple, LLC may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from date.

**What we collect**

We may collect the following information:

  * contact information including email address

  * demographic information such as postcode, preferences and interests

  * other information relevant to customer surveys and/or offers

**What we do with the information we gather**

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * We may use the information to improve our products and services.

  * We may periodically send promotional emails **** about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided. 
  * From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email, phone, fax or mail. We may use the information to customise the website according to your interests.

**Security**

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, **** we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. 

**How we use cookies**

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

**Advertising**

Some of our advertisers occasionally serve you cookies as well. We do not have control over cookies placed by advertisers. We may use advertising service vendors to help present advertisements on the website, one of which is _[http://www.gourmetads.com](http://www.gourmetads.com/)_. These vendors may use cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies to serve you advertisements tailored to interests you have shown by browsing on this and other sites you have visited, to determine whether you have seen a particular advertisement before and to avoid sending you duplicate advertisements. In doing so, these vendors may collect non-personal data such as your browser type, your operating system, Web pages visited, time of visits, content viewed, ads viewed, and other clickstream data. The use of cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies by these advertising service vendors is subject to their own privacy policies, not ours, and Service Provider disclaims all liability in connection therewith.

**Links to other websites**

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

**Controlling your personal information**

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:

  * whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you can click to indicate that you do not want the information to be used by anybody for direct marketing purposes  

  * if you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by contacting us. 

We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen.

**Opt Out**

For information about opting out of Gourmet Ads and ad serving partners please visit _<http://www.gourmetads.com/about/privacy-policy>_

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please contact us.
